Finding Aid for the Nicholas E. Collias Papers Biomed.0432
UCLA Library Special Collections
Nicholas E. Collias papers
1933-2008
UCLA Library Special Collections
Collias, Nicholas E. (Nicholas Elias)
Biomed.0432
13.5 Linear Feet (9 cartons)
Nicholas E. Collias was an internationally renowned zoology educator and ornithologist. Collias worked on his long term research program concerning the development of social behavior in birds with his wife, Elsie C. Collias. The collection consists of materials related to his academic work as a student and professor, field studies, and involvement in professional organizations. Materials include field notes, research article manuscripts, correspondence, thesis drafts, teaching files, publications and records from scientific organizations.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9971280413606533
We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated from the creator's daughter, Karen Collias Whilden, in 2010.
Biography/History
Nicholas Elias Collias, an internationally renowned zoology educator and ornithologist, was born in Chicago Heights, Illinois on July 29, 1914.
After the completion of his secondary education at private and public high schools in Illinois, Collias entered the University of Chicago, majored in zoology and earned his B.S. degree in 1937. Following graduation, he was hired as a research technician by Professor W.C. Allee, an ecologist on the faculty, to study pecking order in chickens. This job led to several fellowships and inspired his doctoral dissertation. Collias earned his Ph.D. degree in zoology in 1942.
Soon after the completion of his doctoral degree, Collias was drafted into the U.S. Army, and served three and a half years. He finished his Army career as a medical research physiologist at the Aeromedical Research Station at Wright Field in Dayton, Ohio.
After his discharge from the Army, he became a zoology instructor at the University of Wisconsin, Madison where he began his long term research program on the social behavior of birds. While at Wisconsin, Collias met Elsie Cole who became his life and scientific research partner. Most professional colleagues and acquaintances knew them as Nick and Elsie. They married on December 21, 1948.
Their research dealt with bird behavior including social hierarchies such as pecking order, vocal communications and external constructions, notably nests. Much of their field research and experiments focused on weaverbirds and junglefowl. Nick and Elsie published numerous research articles, co-authored two books on nest building and were founding members of the Animal Behavior Society.
In 1953 they joined the biology faculty at Illinois College in Jacksonville where they remained until 1958 when Nick accepted a position with UCLA's Department of Zoology. Collias worked at UCLA for 27 years until his retirement in 1985 as professor emeritus.
Nick and Elsie received the Elliott Coues Award for bird behavior research from the American Ornithologists Union in 1980 and the Margaret Morse Nice Medal for lifetime contributions to ornithology from the Wilson Ornithological Union in 1997. Elsie Collias died on December 17, 2006. Nick Collias died on April 28, 2010 at home in Van Nuys, California.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of materials related to Nicholas E. Collias' work as a zoology educator, field biologist and published author of scientific research articles. Collias worked on his long term research program concerning the development of social behavior in birds with his wife, Elsie C. Collias. Their research is best known for its investigations of social hierarchies such as pecking order, vocal communications and external constructions, notably nests. The collection consists of field notes, manuscripts of research articles, correspondence, academic work related to his undergraduate and graduate degrees, teaching materials and records of professional involvement as a founding member of the Animal Behavior Society. The collection also contains publications issued by the United States Army Air Forces that Collias annotated during his service with the Army as a medical research physiologist.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection has been arranged in the following series:
Field notes, 1950-2005
Manuscripts and publications, 1950-2008
Correspondence, 1933-2004
Teaching and research materials, circa 1946-2004
B.S. and Ph.D. notes, papers and thesis drafts, 1930-1948
Professional organization records, 1958-2007
United States Army Air Forces publications, 1943-1945
- Field notes, 1950-2005
  Scope and Content
  Research notes on bird behavior in the field and aviary, particularly on junglefowl and weaverbirds. Countries of field research include the United States, Canada, Africa and Asia. Materials include raw data, photographs, maps, sonograms, graphs, charts, summaries of experiments and audio cassettes of bird songs and calls.
  - Natural History Museum of Los Angeles County, weaver bird specimens, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aviary 1 & 3 maps, nest and egg records, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 22, Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Weaver nest selection, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Weaverbirds, LA Zoo, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Aviary 2 maps, nest and egg records, 1968-1971 (Box 7, Folder 29, 31, Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Rubble nest raw data, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bills and plumages summary, UCLA & LA Zoo, 1978-1983 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bills and plumages graphs, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Weaverbirds plumages & bills, UCLA, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bills and plumages, 1960-1979 (Box 7, Folder 30, 33-34,40-44, Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Weavers, castration and testosterone treatments, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Herbert A. Brown's Weaver Birds, testosterone, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Testosterone injection of weaverbirds, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Weavers, Aviary 1 & 2, Herb Brown, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 51-52)
  - Weaverbirds, hormones, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 53, 56-57)
  - Weavers, Aviary 1 & 2, E.S. Tarvyd, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 54, 60)
  - Aviary 2, R. J. Barfield, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Village weaver sonogram images and photos, 1961-1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Field checklists and photos, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ratite chicks sonograms, slides and photos, 1957-2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Indoor Aviary 1, Barfield & Indoor Aviary 2, Frumkes, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Outdoor Aviary 1, Tarvyd, 1959, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Outdoor Aviary 1, Tarvyd & Outdoor Aviary 2, Frumkes, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Aviary 1, Brian Kahn, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Vivarium and Outdoor Aviary 2, Brooks, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Aviary 1 and Vivarium, Burrows, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 19, Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Nest photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Seattle data summaries of old age in weavers, 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Rubble nest experiment, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 26, Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Non Ploeceinae, East Africa, 1973 (Box 3)
    One box of index cards.
  - Weaverbirds comparative field study, 1956-1957 (Box 3)
  - Ploceus (Textor) cucullatus, 1956-1957 (Box 3)
  - Weaverbirds, Kenya, 1978 (Box 3)
  - T.C.C., Senegal, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Tapes of bird songs and calls, 1977-2001 (Box 3)
    Fourteen cassette tapes.
  - Weaverbirds UCLA aviaries, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
  - Village weaver branch and nest experiments, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 8-10)
  - Red Junglefowl, San Diego Zoo, 1962-1965, 1979-1992 (Box 5, Box 7, Folder 1)
    Box 5: Two shoe boxes of Collias' research note cards.
    Box 7: Collias' notes, data and graphs.
  - Malibu Creek Lagoon, 1984-1986 (Box 6)
    Jonathon Alderfers' sketch book containing drawings of Malibu Lagoon birds and notes for publication in The Auk.
  - Hypophysectomized chicks, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Aviary 3 weekly reports, 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 12-13, 19-20, 23, 26-27)
  - Ploceidae taxonomy and nest building, 1956-1986 (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
  - Weaver nest color regulation, 1974 April 1-1974 July 27 (Box 7, Folder 17-18, 21-22)
  - Aviary 1-3 nest maps, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 24-25)
  - Female weaver hormone experiments, 1964-1967 (Box 7, Folder 28, 45-50)
  - Aviary temperature and rainfall data, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Thyroxin experiments, 1967, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 35-36)
  - Weaver seasonal control, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Effects of testosterone on female weavers, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Aviary 2, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Weaverbirds light experiments, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Aviary maps, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - California field trip maps, brochures and notes, 1958-2005 (Box 7, Folder 54, Box 8, Folder 10-13, 15-17)
  - Weaver finch water economy charts, undated (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Bird display, 1966-1982 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Bird and flower lists, 1954-2003 (Box 8, Folder 4-8, 14, 18, 21)
  - Red Junglefowl - Malaysia photos, 1962, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Female wing length for different races of Ploceus cucullatus, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Manuscripts and publications, 1950-2008
  Manuscripts and research articles by Nicholas E. Collias and colleagues. Materials include drafts of monographs co-authored with Elsie C. Collias including "Evolution of Nest Building in Weaverbirds" and "Nest Building and Bird Behavior."
  - Evolution of Nest-Building in the Weaverbirds (Ploceidae), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Nicholas E. Collias and Elsie C. Collias
    The art work from this article was used for an exhibit in 2002.
  - Village Weaver Ploceus cucullatus, 1974-1999 (Box 9, Folder 25-34, Box 1, Folder 8-10, 12, 16)
    By Nicholas E. Collias and Elsie C. Collias for The Birds of Africa. Materials also include reference literature and correspondence.
  - Social Behavior and Vocal Repertoire of the Grey-Capped Social Weaver in East Africa, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    By Nicholas E. Collias
    Materials also include photocopies of articles by invitation for the revision of Sir Landsborough's A New Dictionary of Birds, British Onithologist's Union and others prepared for press such as "Old Age and Breeding Behavior in 14 to 20-Year Old African Weaverbirds" and "Social Behavior of Unconfined Red Junglefowl" by Collias and his wife, Elsie C. Collias.
  - Comparison of Vocal Signals of Three Species of African Finches, 1993-2004 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Materials also include "Seeking to Understand the Living Bird" by Nick and Elsie and "Inheritance of Egg-Color Polymorphism in the Village Weaver" by Elsie.
  - Some Research Contributions to Ornithology and Bird Behavior, circa 1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Testosterone Versus Psychological Castration in the Expression of Dominance, Territoriality and Breeding Behavior by Male Village Weavers, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 42, 44-48, 55, 58)
    By Nicholas E. Collias, Ronald J. Barfield and Edward S. Tarvyd
    Folder 44 includes correspondence with The Auk Editor-in-Chief, Kimberly G. Smith. Folder 45 includes correspondence with Martin Daly, Executive Editor for Behaviour: An International Journal of Behavioural Biology.
  - Weaver poster paper, circa 2000 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Biographical sketch and statement of research, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Vocal Signals of the Village Weaver: Spectrographic Classification and the Code of Communication, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Understanding Bird Language, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Comparison of Vocal Signals of Three Species of African Finches, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Native Foods and nutritional ecology of the red junglefowl in southeast Asia, 1963, circa 2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Materials include Red Junglefowl field notes collected in Malay Peninsula of Thailand.
  - The Role of American Zoologists and Ethologists in the Development of Ethology During the Three Decades Preceding the Formation of the ABS, circa 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Nest Building and Bird Behavior, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 62, Box 2, Folder 23)
    Includes photo used for the cover of this book.
  - Nest and Mate Selection by the Female Village Weaverbird, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Nicholas E. Collias' response to Peter Garson's critique in Animal Behavior of two of his articles on sexual selection in Ploceus cucullatus.
  - The Importance of the Male, His Territory and His Nest in Mate Selection by the Female Village Weaver, a Tropical Passerine Bird, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    By Nicholas E. Collias, Florence McAlary McFarland, Catherine Jacobs, Janice McLean, and Cathleen Cox.
  - Seeking to Understand the Living Bird, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 1-23)
    Margaret Morse Nice Medal lecture by Nicholas E. Collias and Elsie C. Collias.
  - On the Origin and Evolution of Nest Building by Passerine Birds (Passeriformes), 1990-1997 (Box 4, Folder 25-61)
    Materials include related notes, tables, statistics, photos, slides, correspondence with Dr. Walter D. Koenig and Dr. Glenn E. Walsberg, Editors, The Condor and drafts of Collias' manuscript Ovenbirds (Furnariidae, Passeriformes) and the Origin of the Passerine Bird Nest.
  - Argentine trip talk, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Size Breeding Colony Related to Attraction of Mates in a Tropical Passerine Bird, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - The Male and the Nest in Mate Selection by a Female Weaverbird, 1975-1977, 2001-2008 (Box 5, Folder 11-32)
    Materials include research and editorial correspondence, data, multiple drafts, photos of male and female weaverbirds and their nests. Manuscript name changed to "The Male, His Territory and His Nest in Mate Selection by the Female Village Weaver, a Tropical Passerine Bird" with additional authors: Florence McAlary McFarland, Catherine Jacobs, Janice McClean and Cathleen Cox.
  - Animal Behavior and Population Density, 1958-1969 (Box 7, Folder 4, 10, 61)
  - Weaverbirds public record, 1958-2000 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    Materials include outlines for talks and manuscripts by Nicholas E. Collias and Elsie C. Collias. Folder also contains clippings from magazines and newspapers.
  - Some Behavioral Aspects of Energetics in the Village Weaverbird, circa 1968 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - The Ecological Bases of Animal Behavior, undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Egg Color Inheritance in Weaverbirds, circa 1987-1993 (Box 9, Folder 16-22)
    By Elsie C. Collias
  - An Ecological Classification of Animal Language, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - The Spectrographic Analysis of Sound Signals of the Domestic Fowl, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 23, 38-39)
    Folder 23: One spectrogram photo and two photocopies of baby chick pleasure and distress notes used for article.
    Folder 38-39: Article by Nicolas E. Collias and Martin Joos with related notes and publications on vocal communication in birds.
  - Some Aspects of Comparative Sociology in Mammals, circa 1952 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    By Nicholas E. Collias, Illinois College, Jacksonville, Illinois.
  - Functions of Animal Sounds; An Ecological Classification of Animal Communication, 1950-1960 (Box 9, Folder 50, 52-53)
    Manuscript by Nicholas E. Collias for submission to American Institute of Biological Sciences.
- Correspondence, 1933-2004
  Professional and personal letters to and from Collias.
  - Members of the Section and Division of Animal Behavior and Sociobiology, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Letters related to the formation of an American Animal Behavior Society.
  - Academic Press Executive Editor, Wildlife and Ecology, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stuart Keith, Department of Ornithology, American Museum of Natural History, 1994 August 24-2004 August 13 (Box 1, Folder 11, 13-14, 17)
  - Nigel Redman, Christopher Helm, 2002 September 24 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Marty L. Morton, Occidental College, 1981 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Correspondence includes reprints pertaining to the biology of Mountain White-crowned Sparrows on the breeding grounds.
  - Cathleen Cox, Los Angeles Zoo, 1994 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Correspondence includes Cox's article "Pair Formation in California Condors."
  - R.J. Barfield, Department of Biology, Livingston College, 1978, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 29, 41)
    Folder 29 materials include Barfield's article, "Autoradiographic Localization of Androgen-Concentrating Cells in the Brain of the Male Domestic Fowl." Folder 41 includes Barfield's personal photos annotated by Collias.
  - Oris Payton, Malibu Garden Club, 1985 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Teaching and research materials, circa 1946-2004
      Collias taught Biology at Chicago City Junior College and Amherst College in 1946. From 1947-1951 he was a Zoology instructor at the University of Wisconsin, Madison where he began his research on the development of social behavior in birds. He joined the biology faculty at Illinois College, Jacksonville from 1953-1958 where he chaired the department. Finally, he moved to Los Angeles to work within UCLA's Department of Zoology for 27 years until he retired as Professor Emeritus in 1985. Materials include Collias' curriculum, assessments, syllabi, lecture and research notes, grant applications and related correspondence.
      - Biology 1B, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        UCLA lecture notes for a class dealing with organisms and populations.
      - Biology 274 Seminar on Animal Behavior, 1972-1977, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 27-29, Box 7, Folder 2-3, Box 2)
      - Zoology 264 Seminar on Animal Behavior, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Biology 129 The Behavior of Animals, 1966-2003 (Box 6, Folder 3-26, Box 2, Folder 31)
        Folder 13 also includes exams and answer keys for Zoology 164, 237and 217.
      - Biology 211 Animal Sociology, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 32-37)
      - Sociobiology Seminar, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Biology 26, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Research project notes, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 6)
        Collias' notes on possible research projects and experiments for graduate students.
      - General notes on behavior and genetics, circa 1946 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Bioenergetics notes, 1959-1967 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Concept of levels notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Weaverbird literature notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - Activation of Copulatory Behavior by Androgen Implanted into the Preoptic Area of the Male Fowl, circa 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        By Ronald J. Barfield
      - National Science Foundation grant proposals, 1952, 1980, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 1, Box 9, Folder 51, Box 1, Folder 27)
        Box 1: Development and Physiology of Adaptive Behavior Patterns.
        Box 8: Comparative Studies of Signal Function and Structure.
        Box 9: Experimental Analysis of Vocal Communication Among Birds.
      - UCLA Faculty Grant Program proposal, 1999-2004 (Box 8, Folder 29, 32-33)
        Folder 29: Analysis of Social Behavior in Birds.
        Folder 32: Analysis of Social Behavior and Communication in Birds.
        Folder 33-34: Analysis of Social Behavior and Vocal Communication in Birds.
      - UCLA Council on Research grant proposal, 1991-1992, 1996-1999 (Box 8, Folder 35-36, 38-39)
        Analysis of Social Behavior and Vocal Communication in Birds.
      - U.S. Government Awards under the Fulbright Act application, 1954-1957 (Box 9, Folder 41)
      - National Institutes of Health Research and Training Grants application, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Douglas Oliver, Professor, Harvard University, 1961 March 22 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Letter attached to Oliver's article, "An Ethnographer's Method for Formulating Descriptions of 'Social Structure.'"
  - George A. Bartholomew, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dr. Thomas E. Martin, Editor-In-Chief, The Auk, 1997 April 7 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Jane G. Pisano, President and Director, Natural History Museum of Los Angeles County, 2004 March 10 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Martin W. Schein, Smithsonian Institution Archives, 1995 October 17 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Includes A Guide to the Records of the Animal Behavior Society 1965-1993.
  - E.J. Kraus, Department of Botany, University of Chicago, 1933 February (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Dr. V.E. Hall, Department of Physiology, UCLA, 1966 November (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Nancy Masters, Department of Biological Sciences, Northern Arizona University, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Researchers of weaverbirds, 1987-2002 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Researchers of the Red Junglefowl, 1953-1996 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - National Park Service, 1971 April 23 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Ed Tarvyd, Professor of Zoology, Santa Monica College, 1980 December (Box 8, Folder 20, 25)
  - Professor Henry J. Thompson, Chairman, UCLA Department of Biology, 1972 November 15 (Box 8, Folder 23-24, 26)
    Attachments include Biographical Sketch of Elsie C. Collias.
  - Ornithological Societies of North America, 1994 April 14 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Publishers, 1955-1976 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    Materials concern Collias' book on the ecological foundations of animal behavior.
  - Journal manuscript authors, 1965-1995 (Box 9, Folder 54-60)
    Correspondence concerning Collias' reviews of journal manuscripts for various publications including The Auk, The Condor and Animal Behaviour.
  - Edwin W. Snider, Secretary, National Geographic Society, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 61)
- B.S. and Ph.D. notes, papers and thesis drafts, 1930-1948
  Materials include Collias' academic papers, research notes and thesis drafts while pursuing his B.S. and Ph.D. degrees in zoology at the University of Chicago.
  - The Origin, Evolution and Classification of Birds, circa 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Field studies of social behavior, 1930-1948 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    Collias' notes on various field experiments and research articles.
  - Significance of social dominance in vertebrates, 1930-1948 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    Collias' notes on articles concerning social dominance. Materials include "Group Organization Among Vertebrates" paper by Collias' mentor, Professor W.C. Allee.
  - Collias Review of Nicholson, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    By Nicholas E. Collias, University of Chicago
  - Statistical Analysis of Factors Which Make for Success in Initial Encounters Between Hens, circa 1940-1942 (Box 9, Folder 43-49)
    PhD thesis drafts by Nicholas E. Collias, University of Chicago. Prior title: Aggressive Behavior Among Vertebrate Animals; Some Implications and a Statistical Analysis
- Professional organization records, 1958-2007
  Collias was active in a number of professional scientific societies concerning the behavior of animals, specifically birds. He was a founding member of the Animal Behavior Society (ABS) and in 1964-1965 he chaired the committee that wrote the ABS constitution. Materials include abstracts, programs, newsletters, studies, posters, surveys, lists of fellows, awards and honors.
  - Animal Behavior Society Program and Abstracts, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - American Ornithologists' Union Program and Abstracts, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Animal Behavior Society abstract transmittal form, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - American Ornithologists' Union fellows list, photo and abstract form, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Animal Behavior Society abstracts, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Pan African Ornithological Congress Programme & Abstracts, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)